（案内役）綺羅莉(きらり)様 ご支度は？
Kirari, are you ready?
（綺羅莉）ええ いいわ
Yes, let's go.
（案内役）各家(かくいえ) ご当主様
The heads of each family
are gathered here today.
おそろいでございます
（綺羅莉）
さて 始めましょうか
All right, shall we begin?
〜
MITTENS
（夢子(ゆめこ)）公式戦をしましょう！
Let's have an official match!
（芽亜里(めあり)･鈴井(すずい)）え？
（沙織(さおり)･ユメミ）え？
（清華(さやか)）え？
（豆生田(まにゅうだ)）へえ？
（伊月(いつき)）ちょ… ちょ…
Hold...
ちょっと待った！
Hold up a second!
夢子先輩
Yumeko-senpai!
公式戦の権利は 生徒会長のために
取っておいたんじゃないんですか？
Weren't you saving your official match
to take on the student council president?
（夢子）
あら？ 私が一度でも
そんなこと言いましたか？
What?
Did I ever say such a thing, even once?
（伊月）
言ってねえ！
Oh, crap, she didn't!
夢子に
生徒会長になってもらう計画が！
My scheme to make Yumeko
the student council president...
（夢子）ウフフ
私 そんな我慢強いほうでは
ありませんので
I'm not really the patient type, you see.
さあ 豆生田さん
Now, then, Manyuda...
let's get our gambling freak on!
賭け狂いましょう
（豆生田）ハア…
（るな）
ニャハ ほ〜ら 言ったじゃん
See? What did I tell you?
It's all proceeding without a hitch.
何もかも
うまくいっている
そういうときほど
足をすくわれるもんだよ
That's precisely when you get the rug
pulled out from under you.
さあ 豆生田さん！
Come on, now, Manyuda.
ハア〜
（豆生田）
よく分かった　認めよう
All right, got it. I'll admit it.
俺の計算違いだ
Clearly, I miscalculated.
I underestimated this woman.
俺はこの女をナメていた
この女はギャンブルのために
ギャンブルをやっていたんだ
She was gambling
for the sake of gambling, I see.
蛇喰(じゃばみ)夢子はギャンブル狂
Yumeko Jabami is a compulsive gambler.
その意味は
勝敗に一喜一憂するのではない
Meaning she isn't affected
by the outcome.
ギャンブルそのものの虜(とりこ)
She's addicted to the concept
of gambling itself.
In that case, it's simple. I'm going
to factor even that into my calculations.
なら話は簡単だ
俺はそれすらも計算してみせる
いいだろう
Fine by me. I accept your challenge
to an official match.
公式戦を受理する
（観客）ウオ〜！
（清華）
なんでこんなことに…
How did it come to this?
The student council suffering two defeats
全生徒に中継されている前で
二度続けて生徒会が負ける
while being live-streamed
to the entire student body?
That should never happen, no matter what.
そんなこと
絶対にあってはならない　くっ！
一方で豆生田は
恐らく夢見弖(ゆめみて)を陥れた犯人
On the other hand, Manyuda is most likely
the person behind Yumemite's downfall.
彼が勝てば
If he wins, then a traitor like him
will only gain more power.
そんな裏切者の力が
増すことになる
会長が作り上げられた生徒会が
私の力不足によって崩壊していく
And the student council
that our president built up
will disintegrate
because of my incompetence.
（ユメミ）
夢子ちゃん ルールはどうするの？
What are you gonna do about the rules?
You need to find a dealer.
ディーラーが必要なら
それも用意しないと
I'll be happy to be your dealer.
（副会長）私がディーラーをやろう
（ユメミ）あっ！
What, the vice president?
（豆生田）
副会長だと？
Fine by me. Decide on the rules.
いいだろう　ルールを決めろ
（副会長）
急場ゆえ 手間はかけられない
There's no time to elaborate.
トランプを使った
オリジナルゲームで勝負してもらう
You'll compete in an original game
using playing cards.
名をチョイスポーカーという
It's called "Choice Poker."
基本的なルールは
一般的なポーカーと同じだ
The rules are basically the same
as those for poker.
You'll be dealt five cards, which you'll
exchange one time only. Best hand wins.
５枚の手札を
各自 一度きりチェンジし
役の優劣を競う
使用するデックは
ジョーカー１枚入りの53枚１組
You'll be using a 53-card deck
with one joker.
However, in this game,
you can neither fold nor call.
ただし このポーカーには
フォールドもコールもない
プレイヤーにできるのは
ベットとレイズのみ
Players will only be allowed
to bet or raise.
毎回必ず手札を開示して
勝負することになるが
You will compete
by showing your hand in each round,
より金を積んだ者には
選択の権利が与えられる
but the person who bets more money
will be given the right to choose.
Choose? What do we get to choose?
選択？ 何を選ぶんです？
Stronger? Or weaker? Who has
the stronger hand or the weaker hand?
（副会長）Stronger or Weaker
強い順か弱い順か？
通常のポーカーなら当然
役の強弱どおり勝敗が決定する
In a normal poker game,
needless to say,
the stronger hand of cards wins.
しかしこのゲームでは
選択の権利を得た者が
But in this game,
the person who gains the right to choose
強い役が勝つか
弱い役が勝つかを選択できる
can pick whether the stronger hand
or the weaker hand will win.
強い順なら通常のポーカーと同じ
If you choose "stronger,"
just as in normal poker,
より強い役を作った者の勝利
the person with the better hand wins.
On the other hand, if you choose "weaker,"
the poker hand rankings are reversed,
一方 弱い順なら
役の優劣が真逆になる
and the person with the weaker hand wins.
より弱い役を作った者が勝利する
If you bet more, even a garbage hand
can be elevated to the most powerful hand.
金さえ積めば
ブタを最強の役にできる
ということだ
我が学園にふさわしい
ギャンブルだろう？
Seems tailor-made for our school,
don't you think?
ルールは以上
That's the rules. There's no limit
to how much money you can bet.
賭け金は無限だ
限界までやってもらおう
- Let's see you go down to the wire.
- I see.
なるほど
Even if you have a weak hand,
you can win if you bet right.
手が弱くても
お金の駆け引きしだいで勝てると
（鈴井）
ルールは単純だな
The rules are simple.
役の優劣が逆転するっていうのが
特徴なくらいで
The only thing that sets it apart
is the rankings getting reversed.
What kind of rules are those?
（芽亜里）何よ このルール
（鈴井）あっ
This isn't good.
To think they'd be so obvious...
（伊月）
まずいですね
こんなあからさまとは
Huh? About what?
えっ 何が？
分からない？
Don't you see it?
No matter how you slice it, the rules put
Yumeko at an overwhelming disadvantage.
このルールは どう考えたって
圧倒的に夢子が不利
勝ち目は皆無と言ってもいい
- Her chances of winning are slim.
- Do either of you have any objections?
（副会長）お互いに異存はないな？
（豆生田）ああ
（夢子）結構です
- No.
- Fine by me.
（副会長）
それでは
チョイスポーカーを始める
All right.
Let's begin this game of Choice Poker.
（観客）ワア〜！
（鈴井）夢子に不利って なんで？
The odds are against Yumeko? How so?
普通のポーカーは
In normal poker, the person
with more money has the edge.
より金を持っているほうが有利
ってことは分かるわよね
資金が多い側は レイズで
相手を威圧することができる
With more funds, you can put pressure
on your opponent by raising.
資金面の不安で相手が降りれば
役の強弱に関わらず勝てるってこと
If you intimidate your opponent
into folding,
you can win regardless of your hand.
Poker is known as the game
where you make your opponent fold.
ポーカーが相手を降ろすゲーム
といわれるゆえんね
でも このゲームなら
But in this game, you can compete even if
you don't have the same amount of funds.
相手と同じ額を持っていなくても
勝負できるじゃないか
選択権は奪われるけど
- But you lose the right to choose.
- That's the killer blow.
それが致命的なんです
選択できるプレイヤーは
The player who gets to choose can always
twist the rules to his or her own benefit.
常に自分に有利なように
強い順か弱い順か決められる
言いかえれば これは
Only one player gets a steady stream
of strong hands in this game.
常に片方のプレイヤーに
強い手札が配られるポーカー
私なら
I'd never agree to play this game
unless I was sure I had more money.
自分のほうが
資金があると
確信できないかぎり
このゲームには応じない
バカでも分かる理屈だわ
Even an idiot could see that.
But Yumeko has a ton of money on her,
doesn't she?
（鈴井）
で… でも 夢子も現金は
かなり持っているはずだろ？
（伊月）くっ
あまり生徒会を
ナメないほうがいいですよ
You really shouldn't underestimate
the student council.
（副会長）
チップは１枚１千万とする
One chip will be worth ten million yen.
How many do you want?
何枚 必要だ？
私は現金を
３億１千万円持っているので
Since I have 310 million yen in cash,
I'd like to request 31 chips.
31枚でお願いします
（副会長）豆生田？
Manyuda?
そうだな… とりあえず
Let's see, for starters...
100枚もらおう
I'll buy 100 chips.
- No way.
- A hundred?
そんな！
（生徒１）100って…
（生徒２）10億？
（生徒３）むちゃくちゃだ！
One billion?
That's way too reckless.
The gap in funds is overwhelming.
やはり資金には
圧倒的な差がありますね
恐らく豆生田先輩は
まだまだ余力がありますよ
I'm pretty sure Manyuda-senpai
still has a lot to tap into.
Yumeko...
（鈴井）
夢子…
（副会長）
まずは参加費だ
お互い１枚ずつ出せ
First, your participation fee.
Each of you will throw in one chip.
あっ そういえば
How do we determine which hand will win
if we both get high card hands?
ブタの強弱って
どうやって決まるんでしたっけ？
より弱い役を目指すなんてないので
Since one doesn't really try
to get a weaker card...
If you both get high card hands, whoever
has one more higher-ranking card wins.
（副会長）ブタの場合
より強いカードを
１枚でも持っていたほうが強い
例えば キングと
それ以外で構成されるブタと
If one hand features a king
and other cards,
and the other includes a ten
10とそれ以外のブタなら
キングのほうが強い
the king is stronger.
（夢子）そうでしたね
Oh, that's right. Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
（豆生田）
わざとらしく
ブタ狙いをアピールか
What a phony. Broadcasting your intent
to go for a high card hand... So cunning.
こざかしいんだよ
All right.
I'm going to exchange two cards.
では ２枚チェンジします
Swap one for me.
１枚チェンジ
（副会長）これで手札が確定した
Your hands are now established.
Let's move on to betting.
ベッティングに移る
（豆生田）
蛇喰が捨てたのは
キングとジャック
Jabami discarded a king and a jack.
もし弱い順を狙っているのであれば
If she's going for a weaker hand,
強いカードを捨てるのは
自然な行動
it's only natural that she would discard
her higher-ranking cards.
However...
しかし
you can't rule out the possibility
that she has a three-of-a-kind.
残り３枚でスリーカードが
確定している可能性は当然あるし
Even if her hand is garbage,
she might have an ace.
ブタであっても わざとエースを
残しているかもしれない
弱い順を期待していると偽装し
She's pretending to hope
for a weaker hand
to make me choose a stronger hand.
俺に強い順を
選択させようというねらいだ
俺の手は
ストレートになり損なったブタ
My hand's garbage.
It fell short of a straight.
蛇喰の狙いは 強い順か弱い順か
What's Jabami gunning for...
stronger or weaker?
計算のためには情報が必要だ
I need more information for
my calculations. I'm going to test you.
試してやる
10枚ベット
- I'll bet ten chips.
- Ten?
（生徒）10… いきなり１億かよ
- One hundred million right off the bat?
- Jabami, are you going to raise him?
（副会長）
蛇喰 さらにレイズするか？
（夢子）う〜ん
10枚レイズ 計21枚です
- I raise you ten chips for a total of 21.
- Yumeko has 31 chips in all.
（芽亜里）は？
夢子のチップは31枚
If she loses,
she'll be left with less than half.
負けたら
チップは一気に半分以下だ
（副会長）豆生田 レイズは？
Manyuda? Raise?
（豆生田）必要ない
No need for that.
（副会長）
ベッティングに勝った蛇喰に
選択権がある
Since she bet more,
Jabami has the right to choose.
強い順か 弱い順か？
Stronger hand or weaker hand?
Well, let me see...
そうですね〜
では
強い順でお願いします
Let's go with the stronger hand.
Stronger hand.
（副会長）強い順
それでは ショウダウン！
Now, then... showdown!
（夢子）ブタです
- High card.
（豆生田）ブタだ
High card for both players.
（副会長）両者ブタ
Since she has an ace,
Jabami is the winner.
だがエースが含まれている
蛇喰の勝ちだ
やった！
All right!
That gives her a little breathing room.
これで少しは 余裕が出来たぞ！
（芽亜里）ん…
（副会長）では 次のゲームに移る
Now, let's move on to the next round.
（夢子）う〜ん どうしましょうか
Oh, my, what shall I do? It's so difficult
when you're not familiar with the rules.
慣れないルールは難しいですね
（豆生田）
よく分かったよ
Now, I know what makes you tick.
Unlike regular poker,
huge raises are pointless.
このポーカーは 普通のものと違い
大量のレイズに意味はない
相手より１枚でも多く
レイズしていれば
If you raise one more chip
than your opponent,
それで選択権を得られるからだ
you earn the right to choose.
だから本来 このゲームは
１枚ずつのレイズ合戦になるはずだ
For that reason, we should
be trading raises one chip at a time.
意味があるとすれば
それは威嚇効果だが
The only point of a huge raise
is the intimidation factor,
そんなもの資金力がある相手には
but it's pointless against an opponent
プラス１枚レイズされ
瓦解(がかい)するだけだ
with the financial means
to raise you by one.
When all is said and done, you couldn't
justify the risk for such a move.
結局リスクの割に
メリットの乏しい手
ということになる
それでもあえて蛇喰夢子が
そんな手を打ったのは
But even so,
Yumeko Jabami went with such a move...
狂ってるから
because she's crazy.
Because this woman derives pleasure
every time she takes a risk.
この女はリスクを負うことに
快感を覚えるからだ
事前に話を聞いていなければ
If I hadn't heard about her beforehand,
理屈に合わない行動に
惑わされていたかもしれない
I might've been deceived
by her irrational behavior.
これで蛇喰の奇行も
計算に入れられる
Now, I can factor in
Jabami's eccentric conduct.
礼を言う　西洞院(にしのとういん) 生志摩(いきしま) 夢見弖
Thank you,
Nishinotouin, Ikishima, Yumemite.
Thank you for serving as my launching pad.
俺の踏み台になってくれて
ありがとう
As far as chips go, Yumeko has 42.
Manyuda has 89.
（鈴井）
チップの額は
夢子が42枚
豆生田は89枚
駆け引きで 十分覆せる額だ
She's so close to turning the tables.
Yumeko is sure to win.
夢子は きっと勝つ
今まで何度も
She's won so many gambles against
bleak odds. It's the same this time.
圧倒的不利なギャンブルに
勝ってきた
今回だって同じだ
I'm sure she'll win by some method
I'd never even think of.
きっと僕には
思いも寄らない方法で勝つ
（副会長）チェンジは？
Exchange cards?
う〜ん そうですね
Hmm... let's see.
All right, I'll exchange two.
では ２枚チェンジ
え？
（生徒１）はあ？
（生徒２）10のペアをチェンジ？
- She's swapping a pair of tens?
- What?
（生徒３）何だそれ？
（生徒４）
せっかくの役を
なんで捨てるんだ？
- Why would she discard a pair?
- I don't get it.
（生徒５）訳分かんねえ
（豆生田）
２つ考えられる
I can think of two possibilities.
One, she's going for a high card hand.
１つは順当にブタ狙いの場合
しかし選択権は
こちらが握ることになる
But that would give me the right
to choose.
弱い順狙いを
わざわざ示すのは自殺行為だ
It would be suicidal to show me
that she's trying for a weaker hand.
もう１つは初手でツーペア
Two, she had two pairs in her first hand,
or she was dealt a full house.
または
フルハウスがそろった状況の場合
ブタ狙いと見せかけて
Pretending to go for a high card hand,
she'll make me choose "stronger"
俺に強い順を選択させたうえで
残ったスリーカード
and win with either
the three-of-a-kind she has or one pair.
または ワンペアで勝とうという腹
しかし初手がツーペアである確率は
4.31パーセント
But the odds of her having been
initially dealt two pairs is 4.31 percent.
フルハウスに至っては
0.23パーセントしかない
As for a full house,
the odds would be 0.23 percent.
Even if she did receive such
a valuable hand, would she discard it?
仮にその貴重な手が来たとして
それを自ら捨てるか？
余計なことをせず
She'd stand a much better chance waiting
and hoping I'd pick "stronger."
相手が強い順を選択することを
期待したほうが
よほど勝率は高いだろう
（豆生田）
つまり蛇喰の行為は
初手の確率の低さ
In other words,
Jabami's actions are unbelievable,
because getting such a first hand
is so unlikely
それをブラフとする無意味さ
and there'd be no point in bluffing.
二重の意味でありえない
If she were a normal opponent,
普通の相手であれば
俺が卓につき 蛇喰夢子と
ギャンブルをしているこの状況が
me sitting at this table,
gambling with Yumeko Jabami...
This situation would never happen.
既にありえない
生徒会役員に想定外の方法で
勝ってきたことも聞き及んでいる
I've heard about how she beat student
council members with unexpected methods.
この女はありえないからこそ…
Because this woman is so unbelievable...
（副会長）豆生田 どうする？
- Manyuda, what are you going to do?
- ...I'm gonna get her.
（豆生田）
やる！
You're exchanging five cards?
（副会長）５枚チェンジか？
No.
いや…
I'm not exchanging any.
チェンジはしない
- What?
- Hey, you haven't chosen yet.
ど… どういうこと？
夢子のベットを誘ってる
He's luring Yumeko into betting.
夢子は今 選択権を得れば必勝
If Yumeko gets
the right to choose now, she'll win.
選択権を取るなら
多くのベットをするしかない
If she takes the right to choose,
she'll have bet a lot.
逆に言えば夢子先輩は
On the other hand,
if Yumeko-senpai doesn't like her hand,
自分の手に自信がなければ
降りてしまえばいい
she should just fold.
手札がいいときだけ勝負できる
She can only compete with a good hand.
何やってんですかね 豆生田先輩は
What the heck
is Manyuda-senpai doing, anyway?
あんなリスクばかりの行為
Such a risky move he's making...
バカみたい
What a moron.
（芽亜里･鈴井）う…
（夢子）
ウフッ ウフフフ いいですね
I like that. Is this your way
of throwing down a challenge?
挑戦状というわけですか
そんな気風(きっぷ)の良さを見せられては
Showing such swagger
leaves me no choice but to...
give as good as I'm getting, you know.
負けていられないではないですか
ベット41枚です
I'm going to bet 41 chips.
You're betting everything?
Why is this happening?
（伊月）
全賭けかよ！
なんでそうなる？
（芽亜里）
やはり 夢子の性分が
完全に読まれている！
Just as I thought. He's totally
figured out Yumeko's personality.
レイズ １枚
I raise one chip.
- Jabami, your turn.
- I have nothing.
（副会長）蛇喰 宣言は？
ありません
- Manyuda, make your choice.
- Stronger hand.
（副会長）豆生田 選択しろ
（豆生田）強い順
He answered right away. I admit,
even I'd go with the stronger hand.
（伊月）
即答
確かに私でも強い順にする
夢子は10のペアを
捨てているんだから
Since Yumeko tossed her pair of tens,
odds are that her hand is weak.
弱い手札である可能性が高い
セオリーどおりの王道だ
This is a classic, by-the-book move.
いや… 蛇喰夢子の能力を信じろ！
No, I'm going to put my faith in Yumeko.
If Yumeko loses, I'll be finished, too.
夢子が負ければ私も終わり
勝つしかない！
- The only option is to win.
- That's it for the betting phase. Now...
（副会長）
宣言は終わりだ　それでは
ショウ
Show...
...down!
ダウン！
え？
It's garbage. Too bad.
ブタです
う〜ん 残念
What?
（伊月）な…
- Yumeko lost.
- Are you kidding me?
（生徒１）夢子ちゃんの負けだ！
（生徒２）マジか？
（生徒３）えっ ブタ？
Huh? Garbage?
What the hell are you doing,
Yumeko Jabami?
（伊月）
何をやってんだよ
蛇喰夢子！
（伊月）
お前が勝つことだけが
The only way I could get back
on the student council
生徒会に復帰し
実家を継ぐ唯一の道だったのに
and take over the family business
was if you won.
ハア 終わりだ
ハッ 全部おしまいだ
It's over. It's all over for me.
（豆生田）
なるほど ストレート狙いだったか
I see.
So, you were going for a straight.
そんなもの成立するはずがない
There's no way that would've happened.
さすがに想定外だ　が…
I totally didn't see that coming. But...
I did factor in the fact that this woman
would make an unexpected move.
この女が想定外の手を
打ってくることは計算のうち
蛇喰夢子を常人と同じ基準で
計ろうとするから負けるのだ
Anyone taking on Yumeko Jabami
as a normal person is destined to lose.
４億１千万もの金を賭けるからには
想定外の手が出来ている
"Since she's betting
a whopping 410 million yen,
she must have something
up her sleeve."
そう考え 惑わされる
That's the thought that pulls the wool
over their eyes. But not me.
俺は違う
俺は ただひたすら王道を行く
I always walk the high road.
これは もともと
From the start, this was a gamble stacked
in my favor because I have money.
金を持っているこちらが
大幅に有利なギャンブルだ
If I don't let her trick me and walk
the high road, there's no way I can lose.
小細工につきあわず
王道をたどれば
決して負けることはない！
蛇喰夢子
Yumeko Jabami,
even you weren't a match for me.
所詮 お前も俺の王道にとっては
路傍の石にすぎなかった
ゲームは終わり
This game is over.
And it's all over for you.
お前も終わりだ
Jabami, you're out of chips.
Do you wish to continue playing?
（副会長）蛇喰 チップは尽きた
これ以上 ゲームを続けるか？
What?
なに!?
ウフッ
Sumeragi, do you mind?
皇(すめらぎ)さん よろしいですか？
（伊月）えっ わ… 私!?
Me?
いくらまで出せますか？
How much can you offer?
（伊月）はっ
え？
（夢子）皇さん どうでしょう？
Sumeragi, what do you think?
Well...
そ… それは…
（夢子）
先日 仲間になりたいと
おっしゃっていましたよね
The other day,
you said you wanted to be my friend.
何でも私に
生徒会長になってほしいとか
You said you wanted me
to become the student council President.
仲間は困ったときに
助け合うものですよね？
Friends help other friends in need, right?
お金が尽きてしまって
とても困っているんです
I've exhausted my funds, and I don't know
what to do. Can you help me out?
助けていただけないでしょうか？
フフフッ 皇
Sumeragi, now that you've been abandoned
by the student council president,
生徒会長から見放されて
蛇喰夢子についたのか？
have you aligned yourself with Jabami?
（伊月）はっ
Give it up.
I can still let you off the hook.
諦めろ　今なら見逃してやる
Or do you want to antagonize
the student council?
それとも生徒会と敵対したいのか？
（伊月）はっ！
It'd be just like you to make such a move.
（豆生田）
お前らしい行動と
言えるがな
That's why I recommended you
as a member of the student council.
俺がお前を
生徒会役員に推薦した理由もそれだ
野心
Ambition. The will to claw your way
to the top, no matter what.
何をしても
のし上がろうとする意志
お前にそれを見いだした
I discovered that in you.
野心は努力と成長の礎
Ambition is the foundation
of effort and growth.
上に立つ者として重要な資質だ
It's crucial for anyone
who wants to be a leader.
And it's the thing
you and I have in common.
そして俺とお前に
共通するものでもある
正直言って
親近感に近い感情すらあった
To be honest, I felt something
close to affinity towards you.
Manyuda-senpai...
豆生田先輩…
（豆生田）だが
However...
you didn't have the competence
to realize your ambitions.
お前には野心を実現するに足る
実力がなかった
分不相応
You were in over your head.
Competence equals results.
それだけのことだ
実力とは すなわち結果
負け犬のお前には
備わっていないものだ
As a loser, it's something you lack.
Give it up. You're not qualified
to walk the high road.
諦めろ
お前には王道を行く資格はない
そうだ
I know.
生徒会役員に復帰できるよう
とりなしてやってもいい
I don't mind mediating to get you back
on the student council.
（伊月）え？
自分の実力を自覚すれば
お前にも使い道はある
If you realize what you're capable of,
there should be a use for you.
戻ってこい 皇
Come on back, Sumeragi.
わ… 私…
- I--
- Oh, my...
（夢子）
あらあら 随分な物言いですね
That's quite a choice of words.
（豆生田）うん？
皇さんに実力がない？
You say that Sumeragi is incompetent?
一体 誰がそんなこと
決めたんでしょう？
Who on earth ever decided such a thing?
仮にそうだったとして
Even if that were true, why would that be
a reason for her to give up her ambition?
一体どうしてそれが
野心を諦める理由になるのです？
Because it's for her own good.
それが本人のためだからだ
無能がいくら努力を重ねたところで
結果は出ない
No matter how hard an incompetent person
tries, she can't produce results.
状況を悪くするばかりだ
She'll only make the situation worse.
その努力は無価値
Those efforts are worth nothing.
She's better off giving up.
なら諦めたほうがいい
（夢子）
ウフフ それはどうでしょう？
I don't know about that.
己の価値を決めるのは
皇さん自身ですよ
Sumeragi can decide what her own worth is.
はっ！
Sumeragi,
皇さん
何かを手に入れるためには
まず差し出す必要があります
in order to acquire something,
you must first offer something.
スポーツ選手は
青春を犠牲にして練習にいそしみ
Athletes give up their youth
to devote themselves to practice,
商売人は担保を差し出し
お金を借りる
and businessmen offer collateral
to borrow money.
野心を実現させるためには
リスクを冒さなくてはならない
In order to realize one's ambition,
you must take on some risk.
野心が大きいほど
リスクも大きくなる
The bigger your ambition,
the greater the risk.
That might mean time or the kind of effort
that shaves years off your life.
それは 時間かもしれないし
命を削るような努力かもしれない
This time, it only happens to be money.
今回は
お金であるというだけのこと
Now, then...
さあ！
please make your choice!
選んでください！
無能として安寧を取るか
Either take the safe route, or strive
for the summit by risking destruction.
破滅を賭けて頂点を目指すのか
決めるのは あなたです！
The choice is yours to make...
皇さん！
- Sumeragi.
- What should I do?
（伊月）
どうする？
豆生田先輩につけば
役員に復帰し
If I align myself with Manyuda-senpai,
I can get back on the council,
私は晴れて実家を継げる
and then I can take over
my family's business.
If I align myself with Yumeko,
I'll be fine if she wins.
対して夢子につけば
勝てればいいが
負ければ確実に破滅する
But if she loses, it'll destroy me.
What should I do?
What am I supposed to do?
どうする… どうしたらいい？
（豆生田）
生徒会に入りたい？
- You want to join the student council?
- Yes.
（伊月）はい
前回の上納金ランキングは
見ていただけましたか？
Have you seen
the previous donation rankings?
That should prove my resolve.
私の覚悟の表れです
（豆生田）やめておけ
- You should back off.
- What? Why should I?
（伊月）んな！ どうしてですか？
（豆生田）
生徒会役員の利権が目的だろう？
You're only after the privileges
student council members get.
（伊月）うっ…
（豆生田）
確かに現生徒会の権力は絶大だ
I admit it's true that the current
council's authority is staggering.
金や地位など生徒から搾取すれば
望むだけ手に入る
We can wrest all the money and prestige
we want from the students.
誰も逆らえない
Nobody can resist. The student council
rules over every facet of this academy.
学園のすべてを支配するのが
生徒会だ
I know that perfectly well.
それは分かっています
生徒会に入りたい人間なんて
いくらでもいますよね
There are tons of people
who want to join the student council.
でも 私にはお金があるんです
But I happen to have money.
私は生徒会に貢献できる人間です
I'm someone who can contribute
to the student council.
必要なら
もっと用意することだって…
If necessary, I can get you even more.
（豆生田）やはり分かってないな
（伊月）え？
As expected, you don't get it.
The student council rules this school.
（豆生田）
生徒会は学園を支配している
それは裏を返せば
On the flip side,
学園のすべてに
責任を持つということだ
it's bound to assume responsibility
for all facets of this academy.
How many alumni do you think are
now central figures in Japanese society?
日本の中枢に我が学園の卒業生が
何人いると思う？
彼らは学園に期待し注視している
They have high expectations for
this school. They're watching us closely.
それを裏切れば
比喩ではなく おしまいだ
If we let them down,
it will mean the end for us.
今後の人生におけるあらゆる道は
絶たれると思ったほうがいい
You should assume that every path
to your future life will be blocked.
The student council carries all that
on its shoulders.
生徒会は
その全てを背負う
お前に
その覚悟があるのか？
Are you prepared to take that on?
え…
分かったら帰れ
If I've gotten through to you, leave.
You're better off as an ordinary student.
一生徒でいるほうが幸せだ
（伊月）生徒会長になりたいんです
I want to become
student council president.
（豆生田）なに!?
What?
My father has ordered me
to become a member of the student council.
私は父に生徒会役員になるよう
命じられました
ですが そんなところで
とどまっていたくないんです
But I don't want to be just a member.
I want to be king.
どうせやるなら王になりたい！
そのためなら
全てを懸けられます！
And I can risk everything to achieve that.
卒業生の期待を裏切れない？
You can't let the alumni down?
責任を負う？
Assume responsibility?
Bring it on, I say!
どんとこいです！
生徒会長になるためなら
何だってやります
I'm willing to do anything
to become student council president.
それでも いけませんか？
Still not enough for you?
（豆生田）フッ ハハハ…
同じだな
We're the same... you and I.
お前と俺は
（伊月）え？
（豆生田）確かに大した上納額だ
True, it's quite a hefty donation.
経歴も問題ないな
Your record is impeccable, too.
いいだろう
Fine, then.
I'll recommend you to the others.
俺から推薦しておく
俺たちは王になる
You and I will become kings.
I hope you're prepared, Itsuki Sumeragi.
覚悟はいいな 皇 伊月
Yes!
はい！
（伊月）
認められたと思った
I thought that he'd acknowledge me.
同じ目標
As comrades with the same goal,
sharing the same secrets,
同じ秘密を共有する仲間として
生徒会会長の座という
不遜な野心を持つ共犯として
as co-conspirators in our arrogant quest
to become student council president,
I thought that we were kindred spirits.
私たちは同じ思いを持っていると
でも違った
But I was wrong.
彼にとっては
私も駒のひとつにすぎない
I was nothing but another pawn to him.
Discarded the moment he had no use for me.
不要になれば捨てられるだけ
He'd been looking down on me
all this time.
私は見下されていた
（夢子）さあ 皇さん
Now, then, Sumeragi...
私と共に賭け狂いましょう
get your gambling freak on with me.
I'll get my revenge! 100 chips!
Please add one billion yen to her pot!
（伊月）
見返してやる！
チップ100枚 10億円分
追加してください！
THE GIRL WHO CHOOSES
私こそが
I'm the one who's gonna become king!
王になる！
〜
（豆生田）
戻ってこい 皇 伊月！
- Come on back, Sumeragi.
- I'm about to start seething.
（伊月）
チップを追加してください
（鈴井）
こんなの…
ギャンブルですらない
- What are they saying?
- In order to win, I'll do anything!
（豆生田）
俺は ただ王道を行けばいい
（伊月）
そのためには…
勝つためなら 何だってする！
EPISODE 11:
THE GIRL WHO WOULD STAKE HER LIFE